<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roshan Mehta</title>
    <description>Roshan Mehta personal website.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 19:18:26 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 19:18:26 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Poem, I Love</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There was a poem I learned when I was a kid for a speech competition and I loved it. Although, I didn’t win probably because the other kids were better but the words of that poem stayed with me. Since, after ages, I have forgotten most of it but I still remember few words from it and I tried to retrieve it all but I couldn’t. I also tried to search it on the Internet but never found a hit, probably because it was in &lt;strong&gt;Hindi&lt;/strong&gt; and I have even forgotten the name of the poet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, just like that I wrote those few words I remember on Google search bar and I found it. It was written by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bal_Krishna_Sharma_Naveen&quot;&gt;Bal Krishna Sharma Naveen&lt;/a&gt; and it seems he was a great Poet and even awarded Padma Bhushan by Indian Government.
Anyways, I found the complete poem and I am going to learn it again. 
So, according to my understanding, the poem summarises like this, You, a human is more powerful than the difficult time in your life. You should never get afraid of the bad phase in your life and you have all the strength to overcome every hurdle the time present to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before it gets lost again on the Internet, I think it’s a good idea to keep it here :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;अरे-तुम-हो-काल-के-भी-काल-&quot;&gt;अरे तुम हो काल के भी काल !!&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;कौन कहता है की तुमको खा सकेगा काल ?&lt;br /&gt;
अरे? तुम हो काल के भी काल अति विकराल&lt;br /&gt;
काल का तब धनुष, दिक् की है धनुष की डोर;&lt;br /&gt;
धनु-विकंपन से सिहरती सृजन-नाश-हिलोर!&lt;br /&gt;
तुम प्रबल दिक्-काल-धनु-धारी सुधन्वा वीर;&lt;br /&gt;
तुम चलाते हो सदा चिर चेतना के तीर!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
क्या बिगाड़ेगा तुम्हारा, यह क्षणिक आतंक?&lt;br /&gt;
क्या समझते हो की होगे नष्ट तुम अकलंक?&lt;br /&gt;
यह निपट आतंक भी है भीति-ओत-प्रोत!&lt;br /&gt;
और तुम? तुम हो चिरंतन अभयता के स्त्रोत!!&lt;br /&gt;
एक क्षण को भी न सोचो की तुम होगे नष्ट,&lt;br /&gt;
तुम अनश्वर हो! तुम्हारा भाग्य है सुस्पष्ट!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
चिर विजय दासी तुम्हारी, तुम जयी उद्बुद्ध,&lt;br /&gt;
क्यों बनो हट आश तुम, लख मार्ग निज अवरुद्ध?&lt;br /&gt;
फूँक से तुमने उड़ाई भूधरों की पाँत;&lt;br /&gt;
और तुमने खींच फेंके काल के भी दाँत;&lt;br /&gt;
क्या करेगा यह बिचारा तनिक सा अवरोध?&lt;br /&gt;
जानता है जग तुम्हारा है भयंकर क्रोध!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
जब करोगे क्रोध तुम, तब आएगा भूडोल,&lt;br /&gt;
काँप उठेंगे सभी भूगोल और खगोल,&lt;br /&gt;
नाश की लपटें उठेंगी गगन-मंडल बीच;&lt;br /&gt;
भस्म होंगी ये असामाजिक प्रथाएँ नीच!&lt;br /&gt;
औ पधारेगा सृजन कर अग्नि से सुस्नान;&lt;br /&gt;
मत बनो गत आश! तुम हो चिर अनंत महान!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/articles/2018-03/A-Poem-I-remember</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/articles/2018-03/A-Poem-I-remember</guid>
        
        
        <category>Poem</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Day Not Wasted</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I was quite irritated with my work and was not even feeling like to see or talk anything worth. So, I thought let’s waste a day and just keep lying in bed but I got bored and was not even getting sleep even after trying real hard :) Then, I decided to watch a movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started with a 2015 made movie named &lt;strong&gt;Proof&lt;/strong&gt;. It was an average movie but I was still not getting any sleep. I started with another movie &lt;strong&gt;Gifted&lt;/strong&gt;. This one was very good and it took away all my sleep and I ended up watching three more movie back to back. I could write the reviews about these movies but I feel people on rotten tomatoes and imdb has already done a good job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;so-it-was-not-a-day-wasted-instead-day-well-spent-&quot;&gt;So, It was not a day wasted instead day well spent :)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;task-list&quot; style=&quot;list-style-type: none&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;Proof.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;Gifted.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;Pawn Sacrifice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;The Royal Tenenbaums.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;Hidden Figures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I liked all the five movies I saw today. I could recommend that you can pick any one of these and trust me you will not regret.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/articles/2018-02/A-Day-Not-Wasted</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/articles/2018-02/A-Day-Not-Wasted</guid>
        
        
        <category>Movies</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello World</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I was thinking from a long time to set up my own personal website based on &lt;strong&gt;Jekyll&lt;/strong&gt; as I have heard a lot of good things about how easy it to blog with it. I also liked the idea of setting up a personal website rather using some blogging platform like &lt;strong&gt;WordPress&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Blogspot&lt;/strong&gt; etc, because it gives you lot of freedom in how you wanted to customize it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, today morning I thought let’s do it even though I had other important works pending but it’s okay, I will drink more coffee and hopefully will complete today’s task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I forked &lt;strong&gt;Leonids&lt;/strong&gt; theme, did some changes according to my needs and see I have my personal website ready. It’s easy and I highly recommend everyone to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;so-im-happy-&quot;&gt;So, I’m happy :)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;task-list&quot; style=&quot;list-style-type: none&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;Setup Jekyll based website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it is being setup, I will try to write more and keep it updated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/articles/2018-02/Hello-World</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/articles/2018-02/Hello-World</guid>
        
        
        <category>Thoughts</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
